Abhishek Gupta

Lancaster, England | abhishek.gupta0724@gmail.com | https://abhishek-xavi.github.io/

PROFILE

With a professional experience of 4 years, automation and data-related issues have been my forte. I'm an AI enthusiast proficient in Python with a deep understanding about regression, classification, clustering, deep learning, predictive modelling, feature engineering and Reinforcement learning. Honing a sharp business acumen and a strong analytical mind, looking for opportunities in the field of Data Science and Machine Learning.

SKILLS

Technical Skills: Python, R, MySQL, Oracle, Scripting Languages, Linux, Apache NiFi, Graphana **ML Concepts**: Regression, Classification, Clustering, Random Forest, Word Vectors, Natural Language Processing, Feature Engineering, Reinforcement Learning, Counterfactual Regret Minimization, deep learning

Libraries: Pandas, Numpy, Tensorflow, Keras, Seaborn, sci-kit learn, NLTK, Transformer Models, Spacy

Soft Skills: Collaboration, Project Management, Mentorship, Problem Management, Empathy

Tools: github, git bucket, jira, salesforce, AWS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Visiting Data Scientist

June 2023 – Present

Experian, London

- In depth pre-processing and feature engineering for a big and extremely messy text corpus. This involved identifying messy data patterns, word embedding technique and exploratory data analysis using Seaborn.
- Unsupervised learning was performed on the corpus using topic modelling techniques such as LDA and NMF.
- Advanced NLP tasks were performed by leveraging the HuggingFace library for feature engineering.

Data Science Intern

January 2022 – July 2022

Crux Intelligence, India

- Developed a conversational BOT in Microsoft Teams and Integrated Crux's search engine(Ask) to it.
 The bot was developed on the BOT Framework SDK in python and further deployed on Azure as a service.
- Engineered performance-related issues for the Natural Language Processing module.
- Developed code in ANTLR(Another Tool for Language Recognition) to analyse key performance metrics in business sales.

Technical Analyst

June 2017 – July 2021

Blue Yonder, India

- Responsible for solving data-related issues within the customer database like SQL and Oracle.
- Developed an in-house automation tool Hygiea, which cut down 600 hours/month of manual efforts. This dashboard helped me explore the front-end and back-end aspects of a project and get hands-on experience with Angular JS, C#, HTML/CSS.
- Worked as a deployment analyst for our Products services which helped me hone my project
 management skills. This responsibility involved planning from implementation to delivering the
 environment while interacting with the customer and our internal teams.
- Lead the problem management initiative by working on various performance-related database issues and performing Root Cause Analysis for the same. The work comprised modifying SQL Scripts

- like stored procedures, functions, triggers, and database-related constraints like stats gathering and table re-indexing.
- Delivered training programs in Shanghai for our consulting partners and conducted webinars regarding product features.

EDUCATION

Masters in data science

University of Lancaster, England

- Advanced Machine Learning models involving computer vision, Generative Adversarial Networks and CNN's.
- Data Engineering module incorporating data pipeline development in Apache NiFi and Apache Graphana for Visualisation.
- Big Data Systems modules introducing and implementing data tasks in Hadoop.
- Reinforcement Learning module introducing concepts of game theory, Q-learning, Nash Equilibrium and Counterfactual Regret Minimisation.